Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got an intermediate level lesson for you guys.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节中级课程。
Now Marco, what are we talking about today?
那么Marco，我们今天要聊什么？
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to try to buy a new car.
今天我们要试着买一辆新车。
So we're going to the car dealer and we want to try and see if we can get a new car.
所以我们要去汽车经销商那里，看看能不能搞到一辆新车。
Okay, so lots of great vocabulary for buying that car.
好的，所以有很多关于买车的实用词汇。
Let's check out today's dialogue.
让我们来看看今天的对话。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿就回来。
Hi there.
你好。
I am looking for a new car.
我想买一辆新车。
I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
我有一辆旧的福特平托，想用它来以旧换新。
I see.
我明白了。
You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale.
你这个月运气真好，因为我们所有2010年的车型都在打折。
It is a perfect time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year.
现在是年底，正是买新车的好时机。
Perfect.
太棒了。
I like this one.
我喜欢这辆。
That is the Ford Focus, a very light but powerful vehicle.
那是福特福克斯，一款非常轻便但动力强劲的车。
It comes with dual side airbags, power steering and power windows, tinted windows and your
它配备双侧面安全气囊、动力转向和电动车窗、有色车窗，以及
choice of either automatic or manual transmission.
自动或手动变速箱供您选择。
Sounds like a good car.
听起来不错。
How many miles to the gallon?
每加仑能跑多少英里？
It is a very fuel efficient vehicle, giving you about 34 miles in the city and 40 on the
这是一款非常省油的车，在城市里大约能跑34英里，在高速上能跑40英里。
highway.
高速上能跑40英里。
That is really convenient, especially now that fuel prices are so high.
这真的很方便，尤其是现在油价这么高。
What's under the hood?
引擎盖下面是什么？
A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine.
一台非常强劲的2.5升涡轮增压发动机。
Trust me, this car is fast.
相信我，这车很快。
Now for the most difficult question.
现在是最难的问题了。
What is the price tag for this lovely vehicle?
这辆可爱的车价格标签是多少？
Very affordable, ma'am.
非常实惠，女士。
You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and no interest for the
你今天就可以零首付把它开走，而且第一年免息。
first year.
第一年免息。
You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back.
你现在可以试驾一下，我们回来时就可以签文件了。
Great.
太好了。
Let's do it.
我们开始吧。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to take a look at some of that vocab, especially the one that the
现在我们要看看一些词汇，特别是
salesman used on Language Takeaway.
销售员在“语言要点”中使用的那些。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright so at the beginning of this dialogue we hear a lot of features that this car has.
好的，在对话开头，我们听到了这辆车的很多特点。
The first one is trade in actually.
第一个实际上是“以旧换新”。
This is something that the man says when he goes to the car lot.
这是那个人去车场时说的话。
That's right.
没错。
He says he has an old car.
他说他有一辆旧车。
He has a Ford Pinto and he wants to trade it in.
他有一辆福特平托，他想用它来以旧换新。
He wants to trade in his old car.
他想把他的旧车以旧换新。
So this is something that you do in America or other places when you have a car already
所以这是在美国或其他地方，当你已经有车但想要一辆新车时做的事情。
but you want a new car.
但你想买一辆新车。
And so the car lot, the place where you can buy the cars, they'll usually give you some
然后车场，也就是你可以买车的地方，通常会为你的旧车给你一些钱，
money for your old car and you can spend that money on your new car.
你可以用那笔钱买新车。
That's right.
没错。
So basically you give them your old car plus some extra cash and then you can get a new
所以基本上，你把旧车给他们，再加上一些现金，然后就能得到一辆新车。
car.
就能得到一辆新车。
So that's basically what a trade in is.
这就是“以旧换新”的基本意思。
And well as you said we had a lot of features on this car of the Ford Focus.
而且，正如你所说，这辆福特福克斯有很多特点。
First of all, dual side airbags.
首先，双侧面安全气囊。
Okay so dual side is pretty simple.
好的，“双侧面”很简单。
It means that you have them on both sides.
意思是两边都有。
The left and the right.
左边和右边。
Dual means two.
“双”就是两个。
But airbags are what's important in this phrase.
但在这个短语中，“安全气囊”才是重点。
Airbags do what exactly Marco?
Marco，安全气囊具体是做什么的？
They protect you from hitting the front part of the car.
它们保护你不撞到车的前部。
So maybe out of the steering wheel a bag will inflate if you crash so it will prevent you
所以如果你撞车了，方向盘里可能会弹出一个气囊，防止你撞到方向盘而受伤。
from hitting the steering wheel and getting hurt.
防止你撞到方向盘而受伤。
It's like a big balloon and it protects you from damaging your body.
它就像一个大气球，保护你的身体不受伤害。
That's right.
没错。
So it has two airbags for the passenger and for the driver.
所以它有两个安全气囊，一个给乘客，一个给司机。
Alright so after that we also heard about a number of things that are power.
好的，之后我们还听到了一些带“动力”的东西。
Power steering, power windows.
动力转向、电动车窗。
So what does power steering do?
那么动力转向是做什么的？
Power steering or also called assisted steering, it allows you to turn your car with less effort.
动力转向，也叫助力转向，它让你用更少的力气就能转动汽车。
So maybe you've driven a car that didn't have power steering and so you really have to struggle
也许你开过没有动力转向的车，所以你在转弯时，特别是停车时，真的得费很大劲。
when you're turning the car especially if you're parking.
特别是停车的时候。
So you have to turn the wheel and turn it, turn it, turn it, turn it to turn.
所以你得不停地转方向盘，转啊转，转啊转才能转弯。
But a power steering makes it more automatic.
但动力转向让它更自动化。
That's right.
没错。
So it's very easy to turn left or right.
所以向左或向右转非常容易。
That's right.
没错。
And the same thing goes for power windows.
电动车窗也是一样。
So maybe your car doesn't have electric windows.
所以也许你的车没有电动窗。
So you have to do it manually with a little lever.
那你得用手动的小摇杆来操作。
To turn it around and around and around.
一圈一圈地转。
But instead with power windows you just push a button and the window goes down or up.
但有了电动车窗，你只需按一下按钮，窗户就能上下移动。
That's right.
没错。
And actually as well another feature for the windows we have tinted windows.
另外，车窗还有一个功能就是有色车窗。
Now these are sometimes very popular.
这些有时候很受欢迎。
I don't think I've ever had tinted windows on my car but tint means something is darker.
我觉得我的车从来没装过有色车窗，但“tint”意思是颜色更深。
It's protected from the sun so tinted sunglasses for example can be very dark.
它被用来防晒，比如有色太阳镜可以非常深色。
But tinted windows on a car are black.
但车上的有色车窗是黑色的。
They don't let much sunlight in so you don't get blinded by the sun or so other people
它们不让太多阳光进来，这样你就不会被太阳晃到眼，或者别人
can't see you from outside.
从外面看不到你。
Usually limousines you will see all limousines have tinted windows.
通常豪华轿车，你会看到所有豪华轿车都有有色车窗。
Politicians like to drive around in cars with tinted windows.
政客们喜欢开着带有色车窗的车到处跑。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of features there.
所以有很多功能。
A lot of vocab regarding the car.
很多关于车的词汇。
Why don't we take a break.
我们休息一下吧。
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍对话。
Then we'll be back to talk some more.
然后我们回来再聊更多。
Hi there.
你好。
I am looking for a new car.
我在找一辆新车。
I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
我有一辆旧的福特平托想用来折价置换。
I see.
我明白了。
You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale.
你这个月运气很好，因为我们所有2010年的车型都在打折。
It is a perfect time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year.
现在是买新车的好时机，因为快到年底了。
Perfect.
太好了。
I like this one.
我喜欢这辆。
That is the Ford Focus.
那是福特福克斯。
A very light but powerful vehicle.
一辆很轻但动力强劲的车。
It comes with dual side airbags, power steering and power windows, tinted windows and your
它配有双侧面安全气囊、动力转向、电动车窗、有色车窗，以及你
choice of either automatic or manual transmission.
可以选择自动或手动变速箱。
Sounds like a good car.
听起来不错。
How many miles to the gallon?
每加仑能跑多少英里？
It is a very fuel efficient vehicle giving you about 34 miles in the city and 40 on the
这是一辆非常省油的车，在城市里大约能跑34英里，在高速上能跑40
highway.
英里。
That is really convenient especially now that fuel prices are so high.
这真的很方便，尤其是现在油价这么高。
What's under the hood?
引擎盖下面是什么？
A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine.
一台非常强劲的2.5升涡轮增压发动机。
Trust me, this car is fast.
相信我，这车很快。
Now for the most difficult question.
现在是最难的问题了。
What is the price tag for this lovely vehicle?
这辆可爱的车价格标签是多少？
Very affordable ma'am.
非常实惠，女士。
You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and no interest for the
你今天就可以把它开出这个停车场，零首付，第一年
first year.
免利息。
You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back.
你现在可以试驾，我们回来时签文件。
Great.
太好了。
We'll be right back.
我们马上回来。
So now let's start again with Language Takeaway.
现在我们开始“语言要点”部分。
Now let's take a look at part two.
现在我们来看第二部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So a very, very key phrase that we heard in the dialogue is automatic or sometimes manual
我们在对话中听到一个非常关键的短语是自动或有时手动
transmission.
变速箱。
So automatic transmission, manual transmission.
所以自动变速箱、手动变速箱。
This is very important when we talk about cars.
这在谈论车时非常重要。
That's right.
没错。
So basically the car has a lot of gears and with an automatic transmission, the car will
基本上，车有很多档位，有了自动变速箱，车会
basically change gears by itself.
自动换档。
Right.
对。
So you start in park and you go to drive and you can go to reverse, park, drive, reverse.
所以你从停车档开始，然后挂到行驶档，还可以挂倒车档，停车、行驶、倒车。
This controls kind of the way the car moves.
这控制着车移动的方式。
But with a manual transmission, this means you have to do it by yourself using your hand.
但手动变速箱意味着你得用手自己操作。
So we have what gears?
所以我们有什么档位？
We have one, two, three, four, and sometimes five.
有一档、二档、三档、四档，有时还有五档。
That's right.
没错。
So that's a manual transmission.
那就是手动变速箱。
You have to change the gears manually.
你得手动换档。
It's a lot of work.
挺费劲的。
Now talking about another feature of the car, the client asked, well, how many miles to
现在谈到车的另一个功能，客户问，这车每加仑能跑
the gallon does the car get?
多少英里？
And the salesman said that the car is very fuel efficient.
销售员说这车非常省油。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a very important phrase right now as gas is very expensive in some parts of
现在这是一个非常重要的短语，因为世界上有些地方汽油很贵，
the world and we're concerned about the environment, right?
而且我们关心环境，对吧？
So a fuel efficient car is a car that uses gas very well.
所以省油的车就是能很好地利用汽油的车。
That means that I can go very, very far on one tank of gas.
这意味着我加一箱油能跑很远很远。
I don't need to keep putting gas into my car.
我不需要一直往车里加油。
That's right.
没错。
So usually, for example, sports cars are not fuel efficient.
所以通常来说，比如跑车就不省油。
Hummers are not fuel efficient.
悍马也不省油。
That's right.
没错。
So fuel efficient is a key thing to look for these days.
所以现在省油是一个关键点。
But the customer also wanted to know what's under the hood.
但顾客还想知道引擎盖下面是什么。
So this phrase under the hood is very, very common when we're talking about cars.
所以“引擎盖下面”这个短语在谈论汽车时非常非常常见。
That's right.
没错。
The person said, what's under the hood?
那个人说，引擎盖下面是什么？
And basically what we're saying is what is under the hood, which is that metal cover
基本上我们问的是引擎盖下面有什么，引擎盖就是那个金属盖子，
on the front part of the car.
在汽车的前部。
So you lift that in there, you can have access to the engine.
你把它掀起来，就能接触到发动机。
So basically that's the question.
所以基本上就是这个问题。
What kind of an engine does this car have?
这辆车有什么样的发动机？
Oftentimes when your car stops or you have a problem, like it's broken, someone like
通常当你的车熄火或出问题，比如坏了，像
a mechanic will say, hey, let's have a look, let's look under the hood.
修理工就会说，嘿，我们来看看，看看引擎盖下面。
He wants to know, let's look at the engine so we can find the problem.
他想知道，我们看看发动机，这样就能找到问题。
But in this case, it's not a problem.
但在这个情况下，不是出问题。
He just wants to know what kind of a car is this.
他只是想知道这辆车是什么样的。
Is it powerful or is it not so powerful?
是动力强劲还是不太强劲？
That's right.
没错。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
So that's why we want to know what's under the hood.
所以这就是为什么我们想知道引擎盖下面是什么。
And well, he goes on to explain all the features about the engine.
然后他继续解释发动机的所有特点。
But then when we talk about the payment, how much the car costs, the salesman said, you
但当我们谈到付款，车多少钱时，销售员说，你
know what?
知道吗？
It's not expensive.
它不贵。
And on top of that, you can drive it out today with 0% down payment.
而且除此之外，你今天就可以开走，零首付。
Okay, this is important.
好的，这很重要。
Down payments are payments that you often make with very, very big ticket items, a house,
首付通常是在购买非常昂贵的物品时支付的，比如房子、
a car, things like this.
汽车之类的。
So a down payment is what you have to pay to get the thing.
所以首付是你为了得到这个东西而必须支付的钱。
To begin using it, but not all of the payment, right?
开始使用它，但不是全部款项，对吧？
Right.
对。
So it's a percentage.
所以是一个百分比。
So if the car is $10,000 and the man says there's a 0% down payment, how much do I have
所以如果车是一万美元，那个人说零首付，我需要
to pay Marco?
付多少钱，Marco？
Zero.
零。
I don't pay anything today.
我今天一分钱都不用付。
I pay in a month a little bit and then next month a little bit.
我一个月付一点，然后下个月再付一点。
But if the payment is a 10% down payment, then I have to pay $1,000 today.
但如果首付是10%，那我今天就得付一千美元。
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, it's usually about things that have a big price tag that are very expensive,
所以就像你说的，通常是指那些价格标签很大、很贵的东西，
a house, a car, these types of things.
房子、汽车这类东西。
Usually you need to give a down payment.
通常你需要付首付。
That means that you're committing to buying it.
这意味着你承诺要买它。
That's right.
没错。
So a lot of interesting things going on in today's lesson.
所以今天的课里有很多有趣的内容。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to talk some more.
我们不如再听一遍对话，然后回来继续聊。
Hi there.
你好。
I am looking for a new car.
我想买辆新车。
I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
我有一辆旧的福特平托想用来置换。
I see.
我明白了。
You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale.
你这个月运气好，因为我们所有2010年的车型都在打折。
It is a perfect time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year.
现在是买新车的好时机，因为年底了。
Perfect.
太好了。
I like this one.
我喜欢这辆。
That is the Ford Focus, a very light but powerful vehicle.
那是福特福克斯，一辆很轻但动力强劲的车。
It comes with dual side airbags, power steering and power windows, tinted windows and your
它配备双侧面安全气囊、动力转向和电动车窗、有色车窗，还有
choice of either automatic or manual transmission.
自动或手动变速箱可选。
Sounds like a good car.
听起来不错。
How many miles to the gallon?
每加仑能跑多少英里？
It is a very fuel efficient vehicle, giving you about 34 miles in the city and 40 on the
这是一辆非常省油的车，城市里大约34英里，高速上40
highway.
英里。
That is really convenient, especially now that fuel prices are so high.
这真的很方便，尤其是现在油价这么高。
What's under the hood?
引擎盖下面是什么？
A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine.
一个非常强劲的2.5升涡轮增压发动机。
Trust me, this car is fast.
相信我，这辆车很快。
Now for the most difficult question.
现在是最难的问题。
What is the price tag for this lovely vehicle?
这辆可爱的车价格标签是多少？
Very affordable, ma'am.
非常实惠，女士。
You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and no interest for the
你今天就可以零首付把它开走，而且第一年
first year.
零利息。
You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back.
你现在可以试驾，我们回来时签文件。
Great.
太好了。
Let's do it.
我们开始吧。
All right, so buying a new car can always be tricky.
好的，所以买新车总是有点棘手。
What do you prefer though, for example, in these types of features of the car?
不过你更喜欢什么，比如在汽车这些特点方面？
For me, a car must be very fuel efficient because number one, cars are all bad for the
对我来说，车必须非常省油，因为第一，汽车对环境都不好。
environment, so I want a car that's less bad for the environment.
环境，所以我想要一辆对环境危害更小的车。
But also, I really like manual transmission because number one, manual transmission is
但我也很喜欢手动挡，因为第一，手动挡比自动挡更省油。
more fuel efficient than automatic.
更省油。
And also, I like to have more control when I'm driving.
而且，我开车时喜欢有更多的控制感。
I feel safer in a manual transition car because when you do manual, you actually pay more
我觉得手动挡车更安全，因为开手动挡时，你会更专注于驾驶。
attention to your driving.
注意力更集中。
You have to concentrate.
你必须集中精神。
But automatic, you can think about other things and listen to the music.
但自动挡，你可以想别的事情，听音乐。
So I think that that's a safety issue.
所以我认为这是个安全问题。
But what do you look for?
那你找车时看重什么？
I know you're really, really into cars.
我知道你非常非常喜欢车。
Yeah, I actually prefer manual transmissions as well, most importantly because of the way
是啊，其实我也更喜欢手动挡，最主要的原因是车的驾驶感受，尤其是跑车。
that the car drives, especially a sports car.
尤其是跑车。
It's definitely something for me.
对我来说这绝对是重要的。
It's nice to have a manual transmission.
手动挡开起来很舒服。
But also, little nice features like in the exterior, like the rims, I like nice rims
但还有一些小细节，比如外观上的轮毂，我喜欢好看的轮毂。
or maybe a nice paint job.
或者漂亮的漆面。
Tinted windows, I'm not a very big fan of tinted windows.
车窗贴膜，我不太喜欢车窗贴膜。
But yeah, I don't know.
不过，嗯，我也不知道。
Some cars nowadays, even for, as you said, politicians, they even sell them bulletproof.
现在有些车，就像你说的，甚至给政客用的车，还能做成防弹的。
That's right.
没错。
They have bulletproof glass.
他们有防弹玻璃。
Very, very secure.
非常非常安全。
Well, for me, I don't think I need bulletproof glass, but a good stereo is a good start.
嗯，对我来说，我觉得我不需要防弹玻璃，但一套好音响是个不错的起点。
That's right.
没错。
Yeah.
是啊。
You want to have good speakers and...
你想要好的扬声器，然后...
You can connect your iPod to the stereo now.
现在可以把你的iPod连接到音响上。
Exactly.
正是。
So a lot of great things with cars.
所以车有很多很棒的地方。
And actually, the model that they mentioned, the Ford Pinto, is a very popular but very
实际上，他们提到的那个车型，福特平托，是一款很流行但很糟糕的车。
bad car.
很糟糕的车。
It used to be...
它曾经是...
It was cheap.
它很便宜。
It was cheap, but it wasn't very good.
它很便宜，但质量不太好。
In the 1970s and 80s, this was a very common car.
在20世纪70年代和80年代，这是一款非常常见的车。
And it's famous for being a small, cheap car.
它以小巧、便宜而闻名。
That's right.
没错。
It was a very cheap car.
它是一款非常便宜的车。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
So maybe you can come to our website, EnglishPod.com, and you can tell us if you have a car, what
所以你可以来我们的网站EnglishPod.com，告诉我们如果你有车，你的第一辆车是什么？
was your first car?
你的第一辆车是什么？
And did you buy a new car or a used car?
你买的是新车还是二手车？
That's right.
没错。
Secondhand cars.
二手车。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
And of course, if you have any questions, we're always there on the website, EnglishPod.com.
当然，如果你有任何问题，我们随时在网站EnglishPod.com上。
And we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里等你。
Bye.
再见。
Good drive.
开车愉快。